Food is a backpacker favorite topic.
If you out there walking and burning a lot of calories.
One thing that?s going to be on your mind is food.
So you need to think about it and how light it?s going to be in your pack.
The days of packing out big huge tin cans of food are long gone.
If you thinking about bringing a can of Spam you need to think twice.
At an outfitter we carry freeze dried foods basically its a backpackers convenience T.V.
dinner.
What you do is you heat water and you pour it in and it hydrates, rehydrates in the pouch.
You can actually eat it out of the pouch.
So there is a whole bunch of different flavors and entries and deserts.
You got ice cream sandwiches.
Not a cool thing but it tastes good.
Some packaging you will notice are vacuum packed.
The purpose is behind that is if you?re going to some place of high altitude these will balloon out as you go up in altitude.
The air pressure inside the pack is grater than the air pressure out.
So that?s why they make ones that are vacuum packed.
Eggs you want to have ones that when you rehydrate I refer the ones that you can actually kind of scramble in a pan I think they taste better that the ones that you just rehydrate and eat the bag.
But you don't always have to go this rout there is also things at your local grocery store a Lipton's noodles and sauce Ramen noodles.
Freeze dried vegetables you could throw in there.
Tuna packets.
There is a lot of different ways to do it.
Not just one way.
You have just got to find the right way for you.
If you have any questions give your local outfitter a holler.